Dearborn, Frederick M. (Frederick Myers), b. 1876, collector. Frederick M. Dearborn collection of military and political Americana, Part II: The Civil War and the Confederacy, 1832-1915 (MS Am 1649.24): Guide.
Frederick M. Dearborn collection of military and political Americana, Part II: The Civil War and the Confederacy,
1832-1915.
Houghton Library, Harvard College Library, Harvard University
MS Am 1649.24
Dearborn, Frederick M. (Frederick Myers), b. 1876, collector.
10 boxes (5 linear ft.)
Autograph letters and documents of officers and statesmen associated with the Confederacy in the Civil War, collected by Frederick Myers Dearborn.
60DM-24. Bequest of Frederick M. Dearborn; received: 1960.
There are no restrictions on physical access to this material. Collection is open for research.
Frederick Myers Dearborn (1876-1960), who formed this collection, was a dermatologist of New York City.
Arranged alphabetically.
Autograph letters and documents of officers and statesmen associated with the Confederacy in the Civil War. There are many letters addressed to Pierre Gustave Toutant Beauregard, Braxton Bragg, Samuel Cooper, and Jefferson Davis, as well as letters by them and many others. Some of the letters and documents are accompanied by photographs.
- Aching, V. A.D.s.; near Chattanooga, 10 Aug 1863., (1); 1s.(2p.)
- Adams, Charles W. MS.D.s.; Memphis, 27 Apr 1862., (2); 1s.(2p.)
- Adams, John, 1825-1864. MS.L.s. to Thomas Lowndes Snead; Columbus, 6 Sep 1862., (3); 3s. (6p.)
- Adams, Daniel Weissiger, 1820-1872. A.L.s. to [Mrs. Daniel Weissiger Adams]; near Chattanooga, 21 Aug 1862., (4); 1s.(4p.)
- Adams, [William Wirt, 1825-1864?] A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis; near Bowling Green, 11 Jan 1862., (5); 1s.(4p.)
- Alcorn, James Lusk, 1816-1894. A.L.s. to Maj. George Williamson; Camp Beauregard, 31 Dec 1861., (6); 1s.(1p.)
- Alexander, Edward Porter, 1835-1910. A.L.s. to [Leopold Alexander]; Manassas, 18 Aug 1861., (7); 1s.(2p.)
- Alexander, G. W. A.L.s. to Capt. W. S. Winder; Richmond, 2 Mar 1863., (8); 1s.(2p.)
- Alexander, L. C. A.L.s. to Mary S. Nelson; Macon, 27 Apr 1874., (9); 1s.(2p.)
- Allen, Henry Watkins, 1820-1866. A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis; Shreveport, 10 Oct 1864., (10); 1s.(2p.)
  With endorsement by Davis.
- Allen, Henry Watkins, 1820-1866. A.L.s. to [] Snead; City of Mexico, 3 Dec 1865., (11); 1s.(3p.)
- Allen, William Wirt, 1835-1894. A.L.s. to [Mrs. William Wirt Allen]; Burke City, 30 Nov 1864., (12); 1s. (4p.)
- Allen, William Wirt, 1835-1894. A.L.s. to Lt. M. G. Hudson; Gravel Hill, 17 Dec 1864., (13); 1s. (1p.)
- Allison, Robert D. A.L.s. to William Joseph Hardee; Bowling Green, 5 Jan 1861., (14); 1s. (2p.)
  With endorsement by Hardee.
- Anderson, George Thomas, 1824-1901. Photograph s.; [n.p., n.d.], (15); 1s. (1p.)
- Anderson, James Patton, 1822-1872. A.L.s. to Maj. Thomas M. Jack; Taylor's Store, Ala., 30 Jul 1863., (16); 1s. (1p.)
- Anderson, James Patton, 1822-1872. A.L.s. to Col. L. B. Roy; [n.p.] 15 Dec 1863., (17); 1s. (1p.)
- Anderson, James Patton, 1822-1872. A.L.s. to William Henry Talbot Walker; near Dalton, 9 Jan 1864., (18); 1s. (2p.)
- Anderson, James Patton, 1822-1872. MS.D.s.; [n.p.] 6 Mar 1864., (19); 1s. (2p.)
- Anderson, Joseph Reid, 1813-1892. A.L.s. to Marsena Rudolph Patrick; Richmond, 1865., (20); 1s. (2p.)
- Anderson, Joseph Reid, 1813-1892. MS.D.s.; near Perrysburg Road, 2 Jan 1865., (21); 1s. (1p.)
- Anderson, Richard Heron, 1821-1879. A.L.s. to Col. Edward Manigault; Charleston, 19 Jul 1861., (22); 1s. (2p.)
- Anderson, Samuel Smith. MS.D.s.; Little Rock, 8 Oct 1862., (23); 1s. (2p.)
- Armstrong, Frank Crawford, 1835-1909. MS.D.s.; [n.p., n.d.], (24); 1s.(2p.)
- Ashby, Turner, 1828-1862. A.L.s. to John Letcher; Potomac Furnace, 22 May 1861., (25); 1s.(1p.)
- August, Thomas P. A.L.s. to Braxton Bragg; Richmond, 22 Aug 1864., (26); 1s.(2p.)
- August, Thomas P. A.L.s. to []; Richmond, 24 Apr 1861., (27); 1s.(2p.)
- Aylett, P. H. MS.L.s. to John Henry Winder?; Richmond, 13 Mar 1863., (28); 1s.(2p.)
- Baker, Laurence Simmons, 1830-1907. MS.L.s. to William Henry Chase Whiting; Goldsboro, 21 Nov 1864., (29); 1s.(2p.)
- Baldwin, William Edwin, 1827-1864. A.L.s. to Oscar []; near Union City, 13 Aug 1861., (30); 1s.(2p.)
- Barksdale, G. A. MS.L.s. to Lt. Col. Larkin Smith; Richmond, 16 Apr 1863., (31); 1s.(2p.)
- Barksdale, William, 1821-1863. A.L.s. to []; Washington, 18 Mar 1854., (32); 1s.(1p.)
- Barnes, J. I. Mason. A.L.s. to Mansfield Lovell; [n.p.] 28 Nov 1861., (33); 1s.(4p.)
- Barringer, Rufus, 1821-1895. A.L.s. to Samuel Cooper; [n.p.] 26 Aug 1864., (34); 1s.(1p.)
- Barrows, D. N. A.L.s. to Gen. [] Osband; Jackson, 21 May 1865., (35); 1s.(2p.)
- Barry, William Sullivan, 1821-1868. MS.D.s.; [], 1 Sep 1862., (36); 1s.(2p.)
- Barton, Seth Maxwell, 1829-1900. Endorsement s.; Vicksburg, 8 Apr 1863., (37); 1s.(1p.)
- Baylor, John R. A.L.s. to Charles Colcock Jones; San Antonio, 6 Feb 1873., (38); 1s.(1p.)
- Beale, Richard Lee Turberville, 1819-1893. A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (39); 1s.(1p.)
  Summary of career.
  With signed photograph.
- Beall, William Nelson Rector, 1825-1883. A.L.s. to []; Baldwin, 4 Jun 1862., (40); 1s.(1p.)
- Beauregard, [Pierre] Gustave Toutant, 1818-1893. MS.L.s. to Braxton Bragg; Swift Creek, 9 Jun 1864., (41); 1s.(3p.)
  Plan to counter Grant's rotary movement around Richmond.
- Beauregard, [Pierre] Gustave Toutant, 1818-1893. A.L.s. to [Jefferson] Davis; [n.p.] 29 May 1864., (42); 1s.(2p.)
- Beauregard, [Pierre] Gustave Toutant, 1818-1893. A.L.s. to [William Joseph] Hardee; Pocataligo, 27 Dec 1864., (43); 1s.(2p.)
- Beauregard, [Pierre] Gustave Toutant, 1818-1893. 3 A.L.s. to Joseph Eggleston Johnston:
  - Manassas Junction, 22 Jun 1861., (44); 1s.(3p.)
  - Greensborough, 11 Apr 1865., (45); 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 15 Apr 1865., (46); 1s.(2p.)
- Beauregard, [Pierre] Gustave Toutant, 1818-1893. A.L.s. to Armand Toutant; Manassas, 28 Aug 1861., (47); 1s.(3p.)
- Beauregard, [Pierre] Gustave Toutant, 1818-1893. A.L.s. to Capt. P. C. Warrick and Capt. I. L. Fraser; Charleston, 27 Sep 1864., (48); 1s.(2p.)
- Bee, Hamilton Prioleau, 1822-1897. A.MS.s.; [n.p., n.d.], (49); 1s.(1p.)
- Bell, Tyree Harris, 1815-1902. A.L.s. to W. W. Cluskey; near Tupelo, 16 Jun 1862., (50); 1s.(2p.)
- Benjamin, Judah Phillip, 1811-1884. A.L.s. to [Jefferson Davis]; Richmond, 2 Nov 1861., (51); 1s.(3p.)
- Benjamin, Judah Phillip, 1811-1884. MS.L.s. to Jefferson Davis; Richmond, 5 Jan 1865., (52); 1s.(2p.)
- Benjamin, Judah Phillip, 1811-1884. MS.D.s.; Richmond, 14 Aug 1863., (53); 1s.(1p.)
  With endorsement by Zebulon Baird Vance.
- Benjamin, Judah Phillip, 1811-1884. MS.D.s.; Richmond, 16 Mar 1865., (54); 1s.(1p.)
- Blanchard, Albert [Gallatin], 1810-1891. A.L.s. to Gen. [] Anderson; [n.p., n.d.], (55); 1s.(2p.)
- Bledsoe, Albert Taylor, 1809-1877. A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis; [Charlottesville], 11 May 1861., (56); 1s.(2p.)
- Blount, Robert P. MS.D.s.; [n.p., n.d.], (57); 1s.(2p.)
- Boggs, William Robertson, 1829-1911. A.L.s. to [Richard] Taylor; Shreveport, 22 Aug 1864., (58); 1s.(1p.)
- Boggs, William Robertson, 1829-1911. A.L.s. to Henry Constantine Wayne; Milledgeville, 25 Mar 1862., (59); 1s.(3p.)
- Bonham, Milledge Luke, 1813-1890. 2 letters to [Jefferson] Davis:
  - Charleston, 17 Jul 1863., (60); 1s.(3p.)
  - Same, 28 Jul 1863., (61); 1s.(4p.)
- Bonham, Milledge Luke, 1813-1890. A.L.s. to [Jefferson] Davis; Columbia, 14 Apr 1864., (62); 1s.(3p.)
  With endorsements by Davis and Braxton Bragg.
- Bonham, Milledge Luke, 1813-1890. A.L.s. to Christopher Gustavus Memminger; Charleston, 20 Aug 1863., (63); 1s.(4p.)
- Bonham, Milledge Luke, 1813-1890. A.L.s. to [John Henry] Winder; [n.p.] 7 Jan 1863., (64); 1s.(3p.)
- Bonham, Milledge Luke, 1813-1890. A.L.s. to Gen. []; Richmond, 17 Sep 1862., (65); 1s.(2p.)
- Bonham, Milledge Luke, 1813-1890. A.L.s. to Gen. []; [], 10 Oct 1861., (66); 1s.(3p.)
  With endorsement by [Pierre] Gustave Toutant Beauregard.
- Bootwright, Thomas F. A.L.s. to Robert Hall Chilton; [n.p.] 21 Oct 1863., (67); 1s.(2p.)
- Bowen, John Stevens, 1830-1863. A.L.s. to Maj. G. A. Henry; Camp Beauregard, Ky., 28 Nov 1861., (68); 1s.(2p.)
- Bowen, John Stevens, 1830-1863. 2 A.L.s. to Capt. James Loughborough:, (69)
  - Near Lumpkins Mill, 26 Oct 1862., 1s.(2p.)
  - Holly Springs, 2 Nov 1862., 1s.(2p.)
- Bowles, Pinckney D. A.L.s. to Lida Perry; Evergreen, 9 Nov 1887., (70); 2s. (2p.)
- Bragg, Braxton, 1817-1876. A.L.s. to [Elisa Bragg]; Pikeville, 2 Sep 1862., (71); 2s.(3p.)
- Bragg, Braxton, 1817-1876. A.L.s. to John Cabell Breckinridge; Chattanooga, 27 Aug 1862., (72); 1s.(1p.)
- Bragg, Braxton, 1817-1876. 5 A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis:
  - Shelbyville, 30 Jun 1863., (73); 1s.(2p.)
  - Dalton, 1 Dec 1863., (74); 1s.(2p.)
  - [N.p.] 7 Jul 1864., (75); 1s.(1p.)
  - Wilmington, 14 Nov 1864., (76); 1s.(1p.)
  - Raleigh, 26 Mar 1865., (77); 1s.(3p.)
- Bragg, Braxton, 1817-1876. A.L.s. to [Jefferson Davis]; [n.p.] 30 Mar 1864., (78); 1s.(2p.)
  With A.L.s. from Davis to Bragg, 30 Mar 1864.
  Both letters are endorsements on verso of circular concerning subsistence rations issued by James Alexander Seddon.
- Bragg, Braxton, 1817-1876. A.L.s. to William Preston Johnston; Richmond, 22 Apr 1864., (79); 1s.(3p.)
- Bragg, Braxton, 1817-1876. A.L.s. to []; Richmond, 15 Apr 1864., (80); 1s.(2p.)
- [Bragg, Braxton, 1817-1876?] A.L. (unsigned) to Gen. []; Dalton, 20 Apr 1864., (81); 1s.(2p.)
  First two pages only of longer letter.
- Bragg, Elisa. 2 A.L.s. to Braxton Bragg:
  - [N.p.] Jun 1861., (82); 2s.(7p.)
  - [N.p.] 9 Jul 1862., (83); 1s.(4p.)
- Bragg, Thomas, 1810-1872. A.L.s. to [Jefferson Davis]; Richmond, 28 Mar 1862., (84); 1s.(1p.)
- Bramlette, Thomas E., 1817-1875. A.L.s. to J. B. Temple; Frankfort, 29 Sep 1863., (85); 1s.(2p.)
- Branch, Lawrence O'Bryan, 1820-1862. A.L.s. to Henry T. Clark; Newbern, N. C., 10 Mar 1862., (86); 1s.(2p.)
- Brantly, W. F. A.L.s. to [Mrs. W. F. Brantly]; camp near Shelbyville, 12 Jan 1862., (87); 1s.(3p.)
- Breckinridge, John Cabell, 1821-1875. 3 MS.L. (telegrams) to [Pierre] Gustave Toutant Beauregard:
  - Richmond, 28 Feb 1865., (88); 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 16 Feb [186-], (89); 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 16 Feb [186-], (90); 1s.(2p.)
- Breckinridge, John Cabell, 1821-1875. 3 A.L.s. to Braxton Bragg:
  - Knoxville, 12 Oct 1862., (91); 1s.(2p.)
  - Dublin Depot, 27 Apr 1864., (92); 1s.(4p.)
  - [Same], 3 May 1864., (93); 1s.(2p.)
- Breckinridge, John Cabell, 1821-1875. MS.L.s. to Jefferson Davis; Richmond, 13 Mar 1865., (94); 1s.(3p.)
- Brent, George William, recipient. MS.L. (telegram) to George William Brent; Oxford, Miss., 8 Feb 1865., (95); 2s.(2p.)
- Bridgford, D. B. A.L.s. to John Henry Winder; Orange C. H., 18 Aug 1863., (96); 1s.(2p.)
- Brooke, John Mercer, 1826-1906. MS.L.s. to Stephen Russell Mallory; [Richmond], 4 Jan 1865., (97); 4s.(7p.)
- Brown, John Calvin, 1827-1889. A.L.s. to Mrs. Will S. Brown; Fort Warren, 22 May 1862., (98); 1s.(3p.)
- Brown, Joseph Emerson, 1821-1894. A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis; Atlanta, 9 Jul 1861., (99); 1s.(1p.)
- Brown, Joseph Emerson, 1821-1894. MS.L.s. to Christopher Gustavus Memminger; Milledgeville, 19 Mar 1861., (100); 1s.(2p.)
- Brown, Joseph Emerson, 1821-1894. A.L.s. to Zebulon Baird Vance; Milledgeville, 1 Oct 1864., (101); 1s.(3p.)
- Browne, William Montague, 1823-1883. A.L.s. to Maj. Joseph V. H. Allen; [n.p.] 2 Jan 1865., (102); 3s.(10p.)
- Browne, William Montague, 1823-1883. A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis; Atlanta, 14 Feb 1864., (103); 3s.(9p.)
- Buchanan, Franklin, 1800-1874. A.L.s. to D. B. Conrad; Easton, 28 Jan 1867., (104); 1s.(2p.)
- Buchanan, Franklin, 1800-1874. MS.L.s. to Leonidas Polk; Mobile, 14 Jan 1864., (105); 1s.(1p.)
- Buckner, Simon Bolivar, 1823-1914. A.L.s. to Maj. [] MacClean; Alexandria, 22 Aug 1864., (106); 1s.(3p.)
- Buckner, Simon Bolivar, 1823-1914. A.L.s. to William Preston Johnston; Knoxville, 25 Oct 1862., (107); 1s.(3p.)
- Buckner, Simon Bolivar, 1823-1914. A.L.s. to Capt. L. B. Roy; Estill Springs, 19 Nov 1862., (108); 1s.(2p.)
- Buford, Abraham, 1820-1884. A.L.s. to Daniel Ruggles; Meridian, 30 Apr 1863., (109); 1s.(2p.)
- Buford, John W. Printed D.s.; Richmond, 13 Feb 1864., (110); 1s.(2p.)
- Bullock, Rufus Brown, 1834-1907. Photograph s.; [n.p., n.d.], (111); 1s.(1p.)
- Butler, M. Calvin. A.L.s. to Belmount Perry; Edgefield, 1 Nov 1879., (112); 1s.(1p.)
- Byers, Q. S.' A.L.s. to [William Joseph] Hardee; [n.p.] 12 Jan 1862., (113); 1s.(2p.)
- Callahan, D. MS.L.s. to W. S. Winder; [n.p.] 15 Aug 1863., (114); 1s.(2p.)
  With endorsement by John Henry Winder.
- Campbell, Alexander William, 1828-1893. A.L.s. to Leonidas Polk; Union City, 7 Dec 1861., (115); 1s.(1p.)
- Campbell, John Archibald, 1811-1889. A.L.s. to [Jefferson] Davis; [Richmond] 20 Jan 1865., (116); 1s.(2p.)
- Campbell, John Archibald, 1811-1889. A.L.s. to James Alexander Seddon; [Richmond], 20 Jan 1865., (117); 1s.(3p.)
- Campbell, John Archibald, 1811-1889. 3 A.L.s. to John Henry Winder:
  - Richmond, 2 Nov 1863., (118); 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 6 Nov 1863., (119); 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 13 Nov 1863., (120); 1s.(2p.)
- Campbell, R. M. MS.L.s. to Maj. D. W. Flowence; Fort Morgan, Ala., 3 May 1864., (121); 1s.(2p.)
- Capers, Ellison, bp., 1837-1908. A.L.s. to James Johnston Pettigrew; Morris Island, 8 Feb 1861., (122); 1s.(3p.)
- Carrington, Isaac H. A.L.s. to J. W. Pegram; Richmond, 16 Mar 1864., (123); 1s.(3p.)
- Carroll, William Henry, 1810-1868. A.L.s. to [Leonidas] Polk; Memphis, 12 Nov 1861., (124); 1s.(1p.)
- Cheatham, Benjamin Franklin, 1820-1866. A.L.s. to [Gideon Johnson] Pillow; Camp Brown, 2 Jul 1861., (125); 1s.(2p.)
- Chesnut, James, 1815-1885. A.L.s. to [Jefferson Davis]; Columbia, 4 Jun 1862., (126); 1s.(2p.)
  Includes resolution of the Executive Council of South Carolina, 3 Jun 1862, concerning the withdrawal of troops from South Carolina.
- Chesnut, James, 1815-1885. A.L.s. to [Jefferson] Davis; Columbia, 13 Jan 1865., (127); 1s.(3p.)
- Chilton, Robert Hall, 1815-1879. A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis; near Martinsburg, 25 Sep 1862., (128); 1s.(4p.)
- Chilton, Robert Hall, 1815-1879. A.L.s. to Robert Seldon Garnett; Ashland, 29 May 1861., (129); 1s.(2p.)
- Chilton, Robert Hall, 1815-1879. MS.D.s.; [n.p., n.d.], (130); 1s.(2p.)
- Churchill, Thomas James, 1824-1905. A.L.s. to [Earl] Van Dorn; Camp Bragg, Ark., 19 Mar 1862., (131); 1s.(4p.)
- Churchill, Thomas James, 1824-1905. A.L.s. to Gen. []; Forsyth, 2 Apr 1862., (132); 1s.(2p.)
- Churchill, Thomas James, 1824-1905. MS.D.s.; Fort Pickering, 23 Apr 1862., (133); 1s.(3p.)
- Clanton, James Holt, 1827-1871. 2 MS.L. (telegrams) to [George William]Brent:
  - Pollard, 17 Dec 1864., (134); 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 21 Dec 1864., (135); 1s.(2p.)
- Clanton, James Holt, 1827-1871. A.L.s. to [Mrs. James Holt Clanton]; [], 28 Apr 1865., (136); 1s.(4p.)
- Clark, Charles, 1810-1877. A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis; Macon, 19 Dec 1863., (137); 1s.(1p.)
- Clark, Charles, 1810-1877. MS.L.s. to Gen. E. D. Osband; Jackson, 22 May 1865., (138); 1s.(4p.)
- Clark, Charles, 1810-1877. A.L.s. to [Gideon Johnson Pillow]; Corinth, 22 May 1861., (139); 1s.(2p.)
- Clark, Henry T. 2 MS.L.s. to Jefferson Davis:
  - Raleigh, 9 Aug 1861., (140); 2s.(4p.)
  - Same, 23 May 1862., (141); 1s.(4p.)
- Clark, Henry T. Printed D.s.; Raleigh, 6 Nov 1861., (142); 1s.(1p.)
- Clark, John B. A.L.s. to Col. [] McClean; camp on Red River, 6 Dec 1864., (143); 1s.(2p.)
- Clark, John B. MS.D.s.; [n.p.] 14 Nov 1864., (144); 1s.(2p.)
- Clayton, Henry De Lamar, 1827-1889. A.L.s. to Samuel Cooper; near Atlanta, 14 Jul 1864., (145); 1s.(2p.)
- Cleburne, Patrick Royane, 1828-1864. A.L.s. to Maj. [] Breutup; Richmond, 8 Sep 1862., (146); 1s.(2p.)
- Clingman, Thomas Lanier, 1812-1897. A.L.s. to Zebulon Baird Vance; Sullivan's Island, 18 Sep 1863., (147); 1s.(2p.)
- Clingman, Thomas Lanier, 1812-1897. A.L.s. to Warren Winslow; Ashville, 25 Jun 1861., (148); 1s.(4p.)
- Cobb, Howell, 1815-1868. MS.L. (telegram) to [Pierre] Gustave Toutant Beauregard; Macon, 4 Feb 1865., (149); 1s.(2p.)
- Cobb, Howell, 1815-1868. 2 MS.L. (telegrams) to George William Brent:, (150)
  - Macon, 15 Jan 1865., 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 11 Feb 1865., 1s.(2p.)
- Cobb, Howell, 1815-1868. A.L.s. to Marcus Joseph Wright; Kingsboro, 12 Apr 1891., (151); 1s.(1p.)
- Cobb, Thomas Reade Rootes, 1823-1862. A.L.s. to Christopher Gustavus Memminger; Atlanta, 29 Mar 1861., (152); 1s.(2p.)
- Cocke, Philip St. George, 1780-1866. A.L.s. to Maj. John Taylor; Centreville, 13 Jul 1861., (153); 1s.(2p.)
- Cocke, William M. A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis; Richmond, 19 Jul 1864., (154); 1s.(2p.)
  Endorsed by Davis and James Alexander Seddon.
- Colbert, Wallace Bruce. A.L.s. to [Sterling] Price; [n.p.] 4 Oct 1862., (155); 1s.(4p.)
  Report on the battle of Shiloh.
- Colston, Raleigh Edward, 1825-1896. MS.L. (telegram) to Capt. John M. Otey; Petersburg, 26 May 1864., (156); 1s.(1p.)
  With reply by [Pierre] Gustave Toutant Beauregard.
- Colston, Raleigh Edward, 1825-1896. MS.L. (telegram) to Capt. John M. Otey, Petersburg, 31 May 1864., (157); 1s.(2p.)
- Colston, Raleigh Edward, 1825-1896. Printed D.s.; Wilmington, 4 Sep 1868., (158); 1s.(4p.)
- Colquitt, Alfred Holt, 1824-1894. A.L.s. to [Joseph Emerson] Brown; [n.p.] 15 Jul 1861., (159); 1s.(2p.)
- Confederate States Army - Browne's Brigade. MS.D.; near Adams Run, 3 Jan 1865., (160); 1s.(2p.)
- Confederate States Army - Dan's Brigade. MS.D.; near Petersburg, 31 Aug 1864., (161); 1s.(2p.)
- Confederate States Army - Hospital and Convalescent Camp. MS.D.; [n.p., n.d.], (162); 1s.(2p.)
- Confederate States Army - Missouri Infantry. MS.D.; camp near Shreveport, 27 Mar 1864., (163); 2s. (6p.)
- Conner, James, 1829-1883. A.L.s. to Maj. []; [n.p.] 14 Sep 1864., (164); 1s.(4p.)
- Cook, Hatch. A.L.s. to Col. Charles H. May; [n.p.] 15 Mar 1862., (165); 1s.(2p.)
- Cook, Philip, 1817-1894. A.L.s. to Capt. F. J. Snead; near Fredericksburg, 20 Jan 1863., (166); 1s.(2p.)
- Cooper, Douglas Hancock, 1815-1879. A.L.s. to Col. Robert C. Parks; Fort Smith, Ark., 30 Mar 1863., (167); 1s.(2p.)
- Cooper, Douglas Hancock, 1815-1879. A.L.s. to [Sterling] Price; Sulpher Springs, 14 Nov [18--], (168); 1s.(2p.)
- Cooper, Samuel, 1798-1876. MS.L. (telegram) to [Pierre Gustave Toutant] Beauregard; Richmond, 19 Jan 1865., (169); 1s.(1p.)
- Cooper, Samuel, 1798-1876. MS.L.s. to Braxton Bragg; Richmond, 6 Jul 1864., (170); 1s.(2p.)
- Cooper, Samuel, 1798-1876. 3 A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis:
  - [N.p.] 12 Jul 1862., (171); 1s.(3p.)
  - Richmond, 9 Nov 1861., (172); 1s.(3p.)
  - [N.p.] 5 Feb 1865., (173); 1s.(2p.)
- Cooper, Samuel, 1798-1876. MS.L. (unsigned transcript) to Joseph Eggleston Johnston; Richmond, 3 Jan 1862., (174); 1s.(2p.)
  With autograph note by Johnston.
- Cooper, Samuel, 1798-1876. 2 MS.L.s. to James Alexander Seddon:
  - [N.p.] 2 Nov 1863., (175); 2s.(5p.)
  - Richmond, 27 Jan 1865., (176); 1s.(2p.)
- Cooper, Samuel, 1798-1876. A.L.s. to []; Richmond, 2 Feb 1865., (177); 1s.(4p.)
  Endorsed by Jefferson Davis.
- Cooper, Samuel, 1798-1876. A.L.s. to []; Washington, 25 Jan 1861., (178); 1s.(1p.)
- Cooper, Samuel, 1798-1876. MS.D.s.; Montgomery, 6 Apr 1861., (179); 1s.(1p.)
- Cooper, Samuel, 1798-1876. MS.D.s.; Richmond, 16 Nov 1861., (180); 1s.(2p.)
- Corse, Montgomery Dent, 1816-1895. MS.L.s. to Maj. C. Pickett; Kinston, 21 Apr 1864., (181); 1s.(2p.)
- Cosby, George Blake, 1830-1909. 2 A.L.s. to James Birdseye McPherson:
  - Near Raymond, Miss., 25 Nov 1863., (182); 1s.(1p.)
  - Cosby's Bridge, 5 Dec 1863., (183); 1s.(1p.)
- Cox, John Z. A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis; Richmond, 24 Jun 1864., (184); 1s.(4p.)
- Cox, William Ruffin, 1832-1919. A.MS.s.; [n.p., n.d.], (185); 1s.(1p.)
- Crittenden, George Bibb, 1812-1880. Cut autograph; [n.p.] 8 Jun 1864., (186); 1s.(1p.)
- Crowly, R. A. A.L.s. to P. W. Smith; Richmond, 11 Aug 1863., (187); 1s.(2p.)
- Cumming, William Henry. A.L.s. to Col. L. B. Roy; near Salkehatchie, 28 Jan 1865., (188); 1s.(2p.)
- Dangan, E. Keith. MS.D.s.; James Island, 10 Jan 1865., (189); 1s.(1p.)
- Daniel, Junius, 1828-1864. Printed D.s.; near Orange C. H., 1 Jan 1864., (190); 1s.(2p.)
- Davidson, Henry Brevard, 1831-1899. A.L.s. to Gustavus Woodson Smith; Staunton, 23 Sep [1862]., (191); 1s.(1p.)
- Davidson, Hunter. A.L.s. to Capt. G. W. Alexander; [n.p.] 12 Aug 1863., (192); 1s.(2p.)
- Davidson, Hunter. A.D.s.; 10 Aug 1863., (193); 1s.(2p.)
  Endorsed by John Henry Winder.
- Davis, George, 1820-1896. 2 MS.L.s. to [Jefferson Davis]:
  - Richmond, 2 Dec 1864., (194); 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 9 Dec 1864., (195); 1s.(1p.)
- Davis, George, 1820-1896. A.L.s. to Zebulon Baird Vance; Richmond, 22 Jan 1864., (196); 1s.(2p.)
- Davis, Jefferson, 1808-1889. A.L.s. to Braxton Bragg; Richmond, 18 Aug 1864., (197); 1s.(2p.)
- Davis, Jefferson, 1808-1889. A.L.s. to Howell Cobb; [Montgomery?], 12 Mar 1861., (198); 1s.(1p.)
- Davis, Jefferson, 1808-1889. A.L.s. to [Howell Cobb?]; Richmond, 5 Feb 1862., (199); 1s.(1p.)
- Davis, Jefferson, 1808-1889. MS.L.s. to House of Representatives, C.S.A.; Richmond, 1 May 1863., (200); 1s.(2p.)
- Davis, Jefferson, 1808-1889. A.L.s. to George Howard; Montgomery, 1 Apr 1861., (201); 1s.(1p.)
- Davis, Jefferson, 1808-1889. 2 A.L.s. to Joseph Eggleston Johnston:
  - Richmond, 20 Aug 1861., (202); 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 11 Jul 1864., (203); 1s.(4p.)
- Davis, Jefferson, 1808-1889. MS.L.s. to James Alexander Seddon; Richmond, 1 Feb 1865., (204); 5s.(5p.)
- Davis, Jefferson, 1808-1889. MS.L.s. to Senate, C.S.A.; Richmond, 26 Nov 1864., (205); 1s.(2p.)
  With MS.L.s. to Jefferson Davis from Howell Cobb.
- Davis, Jefferson, 1808-1889. A.L.s. [fragment: endorsement]; Aug 1862., (206); 1s.(1p.)
- Davis, Jefferson, 1808-1889, recipient. MS.L. (unsigned) to [Jefferson Davis]; Tullahoma? 12 Feb 1863., (207); 1s.(2p.)
- Davis, Joseph Robert, 1825-1896. 3 A.L.s. to [Jefferson Davis?]:
  - Near Petersburg, 3 Jul 1864., (208); 1s.(3p.)
  - [N.p.] 10 Sep [1864?], (209); 1s.(4p.)
  - [N.p.] 29 Mar 1865., (210); 1s.(1p.)
- De Bray, Xavier Blanchard. A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], (211); 1s.(1p.)
- De Langnel, Julius Adolph, 1827-1912. A.L.s. to Col. Josiah Gorgas; Richmond, 3 Feb 1864., (212); 1s.(4p.)
- De Leon, Edwin. A.L.s. to Jefferson Davis; Paris, 9 May 1863., (213); 1s.(4p.)
- Deshler, James, 1833-1863. A.L.s. to [] Deshler; Fort Wise, Ky., 3 Mar 1861., (214); 1s.(4p.)
- Devereux, John G. A.D.s.; New Orleans, 13 Sep 1861., (215); 1s.(2p.)
- Dibrell, George Gibbs, 1822-1888. A.L.s. to Lt. [] Barthelmess; [n.p.] 29 Jun 1864., (216); 1s.(2p.)
- Dickinson, B. F. Printed D.s.; [n.p.] 27 Nov 1861., (217); 1s.(2p.)
- Dimmock, Charles. A.L.s. to Daniel Ruggles; Richmond, 29 May 1861., (218); 1s.(2p.)
- Dobbins, Archibald J. A.L.s. to Maj. J. King; [n.p.] 14 Oct 1864., (219); 1s.(2p.)
- Dockery, Thomas Pleasant, 1833-1898. A.L.s. to Col. J. F. Belton; Monticello, Ark., 19 Aug 1864., (220); 1s.(2p.)
- Doles, George Pierce, 1830-1864. A.L.s. to [Henry Constantine?] Wayne; near Norfolk, 2 Jul 1861., (221); 1s.(2p.)
- [Doles, George Pierce, 1830-1864.] A.L.s. (Geo) to Howard []; near Martinsburg, 23 Sep 1862., (222); 2s.(6p.)
- Donelson, Daniel Smith, 1801-1863. A.L.s. to Gen. [] Jackson; Green Ridge, 16 Oct 1861., (223); 1s.(2p.)
- Donelson, Daniel Smith, 1801-1863. A.L.s. to Gideon Johnson Pillow; [], 31 May 1861., (224); 1s.(1p.)
- Donelson, J. S. A.L.s. to []; near Shelbyville, 23 Apr 1863., (225); 1s.(2p.)
- Drayton, Thomas Fenwick, 1808-1891. A.D.s.; Charleston, 23 Apr 1861., (226); 1s.(2p.)
- Drayton, Thomas Fenwick, 1808-1891. MS.D.s.; Camp Bragg, Ark., 31 Oct 1863., (227); 1s.(2p.)
- Du Bose, Dudley McIver, 1834-1883. A.L.s. to [] Porter; Washington, Ga., 5 Sep 1866., (228); 1s.(4p.)
- Duffel, John E. MS.D.s.; Lynchburg, 3 Nov 1863., (229); 1s.(1p.)
- Duncan, Johnson Kelly, 1827-1862. A.L.s. to Lt. John G. Devereux; New Orleans, 17 Sep 1861., (230); 1s.(4p.)
- Duncan, Johnson Kelly, 1827-1862. A.L.s. to Col. Ignatius Syzmanski; Forts Jackson and St. Philip, 9 Apr 1862., (231); 1s.(1p.)
- Dunmore, Earl. A.L.s. to [Jefferson Davis]; Montreal, [n.d.], (232); 2s.(4p.)